SANUSI BELLO

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

- rafiubello4real@gmail.com
- (+234)8027365891
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/bello-olaniyan-42626b1b6
- https://github.com/TunarshBee
- https://sanbello.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over 3 years of experience in JavaScript, Node, React, CICD development and as a problem solver who loves facing challenges in my work, I'm excited to be at the deployment phase of my career as a web developer. I'm passionate and ambitious about my work, and love to be on a team that questions possibilities. I've previously been a graphics designer, and bring those skills to my UI development on a team. Independently, I've accomplished website building projects as a freelancer for over two years.

EDUCATION

 Bachelor of Science, Physics University of Ilorin (UNILORIN) Kwara State

RELEVANT COURSES

- Data Structures
- Algorithm Design
- Database Management
- Systems
- Creation of API with Node
- Firebase 9
- Software Design Methodology
- Bootcamp JavaScript Courses

KEY SKILLS

- Fluent and experienced in different programming languages; scripting, structural (functional), and object-oriented.
- Extensive experience developing solutions for web across various operating systems, databases and platforms.
- Familiarity with development & release tooling (i.e. /Webpack/Github)
- Expertise in various open-source framework and other development tools Vue, React etc
- Ability to bring ideas and design solutions to life through the system development process.
- Expert in building web applications using PLAMP stack (Linux, Apache, PHP, MYSOL)
- Extensive experience in application development using HTML5, JavaScript, WebSockets and CSS3.
- Strong knowledge and hands-on skills in SQL server database development.
- Experience in designing responsive custom web pages
- Experience with REST API design

- Experience working with authenticated, customer focused applications
- Experience integrating hardware and software
- Ability to work independently and identify and solve problems effectively and efficiently.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

Advance JavaScript Functional Programming Patterns
Udemy. In view

JavaScript Certification
HackerRank

Problem Solving Certification
HackerRank

CSS Certification
HackerRank

Responsive Web Design Certificate freeCodeCamp

Node Js Skills Test
Turing

React Js Skills Test
Turing

React (16.8+) Skills Test Turing React Skills Certification HackerRank

Front-end Fundaementals
Pirple.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

KHRISTFIX TECHNOLOGIES, IBADAN NIGERIA, FULL-STACK DEVELOPER. January 2021 – TILL DATE.

- Frontend development using React Js, HTML5, CSS3
- Backend development using Node Js, MongoDB and Express framework
- Prepare Technical Design and Specification documents
- Collaborate with the development team, support, and business on day to day development requests and support
- Prepare documentation and use case scenarios when required
- Leads solution designs, documents architecture proposals and creates high-level design Documents
- Lead technical solution sessions to ensure that solutions are complete, scalable and are future-Proof
- Helps determine coding standards along with the senior development team and ensures consistent adoption by developers

 Conducts code reviews, mentors and coaches the larger team, provides objective feedback to consultants and development partners to ensure proper execution of projects.

FOREMAN TECHNOLOGIES, SAKI NIGERIA, SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER December 2020 – July 2021

- Participate in the entire application lifecycle, focusing on coding and debugging
- Write clean code to develop functional web applications
- Troubleshoot and debug applications
- Perform UI tests to optimize performance
- Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications
- Collaborate with Back-end developers to integrate API endpoints
- Gather and address technical and design requirements
- Provide training and support to internal teams
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Liaise with developers, designers and system administrators to identify new features
- Follow emerging technologies

AS-SUNNAH ENTERPRISE, ILORIN NIGERIA, DATA ANALYST

January 2018 – December 2020

- Interpret data, analyze results using statistical techniques and provide ongoing reports
- Develop and implement databases, data collection systems, data analytics and other strategies that optimize statistical efficiency and quality
- Acquire data from primary or secondary data sources and maintain databases/data systems
- Identify, analyze, and interpret trends or patterns in complex data sets
- Filter and "clean" data by reviewing computer reports, printouts, and performance indicators to locate and correct code problems
- Work with management to prioritize business and information needs
- Locate and define new process improvement opportunities

OKITECH CYBER CAFÉ, SAKI NIGERIA, WEB DEVELOPER

August 2015 - December 2018

- Design, test, code and deliver high quality secure production software with completely automated tests suitable for cloud deployment at scale
- Write clean, well-documented, and well-tested code using Test-Driven-Development.
- Develop automated tests (TDD including unit or behavioral test, integration test, acceptance tests) to achieve test coverage for continuous deployment and near 100% availability.
- Collaborate with CTO and Product Manager to refine epics, user stories and acceptance criteria
- Minimize technical debt and continuously improve and learn from mistakes, bugs and refactoring.
- Work in small deliverable batches Conduct research, spikes, design, prototyping and other innovation, exploration and learning activities.
- Eliminate distractions, impediments and wasteful work to optimize flow and velocity.
- Use software engineering best practices to ensure a high standard of quality.
- Help the team succeed in delivering potentially releasable and production ready software artifacts in every iteration.
- You will be assisting with technical direction, utilizing modern technology and Agile best practice to help create and deliver cutting-edge.
- Review & compare different technical solutions and applications/tools, and recommend the best considering security, performance, scalability and maintainability of solutions on Salesforce.

PERSONAL / OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

- **Mazaryn** An open-source social application that implements blockchain technology for transactions among members of the application. (React, Python Django, PostgreSQL).
- **Trans-Logistics** A logistic application that allows users to send and receive goods and parcels across the nation. (React, Node JS and MongoDB).
- **JavaScript-Land-Community** An open-source application for javaScript that allows users to search for and create video recordings through the world (Next, Node and Mongo)
- **Tube-Pro** A personal project that grant users access to videos regarding their search terms integrated with YouTube API (React and CSS).
- **Sea-food-store** An e-commerce website where clients are able to load available sea foods and add it to their cart and it was made editable (React, Firebase and Stylus).
- **Message-Encryption** A web-based application for encrypting messages into links which can be decrypted only by the person that has the link (JavaScript, CSS and HTML).
- **Movie-Comparer** A website for comparing two movies in order to know which one more rated, built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Axios, bulma, OMDB API and Fontawesome
- **To-do app** A React JS web application for where users can create new tasks, delete an existing one and ticking the completed ones out. Built with React js, CSS, Axios and UUID.
- **Blog Post** An online blog platform, built with Node js framework, MongoDB, EJS, lodash, Morgan, FireBase and Express Js.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language

- JavaScript
- C
- PHP
- C++
- TypeScript
- MatLab

Operating System

- Windows
- Linux

Databases

SQL

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- SQL

NoSQL

- MongoDB
- FireBase

Hosting Platform

- Heroku
- Netlify
- Vercel
- Github

Frameworks / Libraries

- React
- Hooks
- Vue
- jQuery
- Redux
- Redux-Saga
- Redux-Thunk
- Morgan
- Node JS
- Express
- Axios
- Webflow
- Webpack
- Gulp
- Lodash
- EJS
- Material UI
- Ajax
- Formik
- Stylus
- Styled Components
- Chakra UI
- Semantic UI

Markup Languages

- HTML
- XHTML
- kML

Styling Technologies

- CSS
- Tailwind CSS
- Sass
- Bulma CSS

Other Technologies / Skils

- Glt
- CorelDraw
- Jira
- Adobe XD
- Github
- Kanban
- PowerShell
- Bash
- Adobe Photoshop
- Command Prompt
- Microsoft Office